{
    "time": 30,
    "maxQuestions": 50,
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The first petroleum Company in Nigeria is",
            "options": [
                "Mobil",
                "Agip",
                "Texaco",
                "Shell"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Shell"
        },
        {
            "question": "Petroleum is made up of mainly",
            "options": [
                "Carbon and hydrogen",
                "Sodium and magnesium",
                "Sodium and calcium",
                "mercury and Iron"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Carbon and hydrogen"
        },
        {
            "question": "General studies programmes were adopted by NUC in",
            "options": [
                "1992",
                "1969",
                "1989",
                "1980"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1989"
        },
        {
            "question": "Petroleum is formed by",
            "options": [
                "decomposition of marine microorganisms",
                "Decomposition of atoms and electrons",
                "decomposition of oil",
                "decomposition of water element microorganisms"
            ],
            "correctOption": "decomposition of marine microorganisms"
        },
        {
            "question": "Colonialism played a negative role in our quest for technological development except",
            "options": [
                "The people were colonized",
                "it lead to explosion of science",
                "their early technological feat were eroded",
                "Talented Nigerian were taken away"
            ],
            "correctOption": "it lead to explosion of science"
        },
        {
            "question": "Establishment of car assembly plants, pharmaceutical industries etc in Nigeria by the developed nations",
            "options": [
                "Are good evidences of transfer of technology",
                "highly encourages transfer of technology",
                "does not constitute transfer of technology",
                "is prevalent"
            ],
            "correctOption": "does not constitute transfer of technology"
        },
        {
            "question": "An educated person is expected to be",
            "options": [
                "myopic",
                "versatile",
                "exceptional",
                "average"
            ],
            "correctOption": "versatile"
        },
        {
            "question": "The device used to store electric charges is",
            "options": [
                "Inductor",
                "transistor",
                "resister",
                "capacitors"
            ],
            "correctOption": "capacitors"
        },
        {
            "question": "The first Nigeria to win a Nobel prize is",
            "options": [
                "Sofowora",
                "Emegwali",
                "Chinua Achebe",
                "Wole Soyinka"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Wole Soyinka"
        },
        {
            "question": "The instrument used to measure current is",
            "options": [
                "ammeter",
                "transformer",
                "voltmeter",
                "choke"
            ],
            "correctOption": "ammeter"
        },
        {
            "question": "The radiation with the highest range in air is",
            "options": [
                "cosmic ray",
                "Alpha particle",
                "gamma ray",
                "x-ray"
            ],
            "correctOption": "gamma ray"
        },
        {
            "question": "The University in Nigeria that is center for automobile research is",
            "options": [
                "Unilag",
                "ABU",
                "UI",
                "UNN"
            ],
            "correctOption": "ABU"
        },
        {
            "question": "Religion is a factor in technological development in Nigeria because.",
            "options": [
                "There is agreement in belief",
                "There is suspicion of one another",
                "Useful and precious times are put in religious matters.",
                "It encourages development"
            ],
            "correctOption": "There is suspicion of one another"
        },
        {
            "question": "Work done is the",
            "options": [
                "sum of force and displacement",
                "Product of force and displacement",
                "difference of power and energy",
                "ratio of force and time"
            ],
            "correctOption": "difference of power and energy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Product of force and A current of 8A flows across a metallic conductor of resistance 5 Ohms, the voltage across the conductor.",
            "options": [
                "1.6V",
                "13V",
                "40V",
                "30V"
            ],
            "correctOption": "40V"
        },
        {
            "question": "The seat belt in the car is in obedience to Newton's",
            "options": [
                "3rd Law of motion",
                "2nd Law of motion",
                "kepler's law",
                "1st law of motion"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3rd Law of motion"
        },
        {
            "question": "Advantages of Hydroelectric plant include the following except",
            "options": [
                "No atmospheric pollution",
                "It is noiseless",
                "It offers flood control and irrigation at the same time",
                "It is one of the cheaper way of producing large electricity"
            ],
            "correctOption": "It is noiseless"
        },
        {
            "question": "The forces keeping the planets in their respective elliptical orbits around the sun are",
            "options": [
                "centripetal and centrifugal",
                "gravitational and centripetal",
                "friction and centrifugal",
                "Centripetal and friction"
            ],
            "correctOption": "gravitational and centripetal"
        },
        {
            "question": "The electrical power is given by one of the following formulas",
            "options": [
                "IV",
                "I^2R^2",
                "I^2V^2",
                "IR^2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "IV"
        },
        {
            "question": "The city in Nigeria that is making effort for us to have made in Nigeria car is",
            "options": [
                "Nnewi",
                "Ibadan",
                "Kano",
                "Owerri"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Nnewi"
        },
        {
            "question": "The electric generator consists essentially of the following except",
            "options": [
                "rectangular armature",
                "Cylindrical soft iron core",
                "a triangular soft iron armature",
                "a powerful permanent magnet"
            ],
            "correctOption": "a triangular soft iron armature"
        },
        {
            "question": "The starting point for our technological take-off as a nation is for her to pay attention to",
            "options": [
                "liberal arts education",
                "vocational and technical education",
                "Arts education",
                "social science education"
            ],
            "correctOption": "vocational and technical education"
        },
        {
            "question": "An object makes a displacement of 100m is 5s. the velocity of the object is",
            "options": [
                "20m/s",
                "2.5/m",
                "5m/s",
                "10m/s"
            ],
            "correctOption": "20m/s"
        },
        {
            "question": "The policy for establishing the gifted children secondary school is to",
            "options": [
                "Help less privileged children",
                "To have balanced education",
                "To catch the geniuses young",
                "To encourage education in the states"
            ],
            "correctOption": "To catch the geniuses young"
        },
        {
            "question": "Energy can be defined as",
            "options": [
                "ability to do work",
                "ability to see food",
                "ability to do pressure",
                "ability to sleep"
            ],
            "correctOption": "ability to do work"
        },
        {
            "question": "The most common sources of sustainable energy today are",
            "options": [
                "wind and sound",
                "Coal and petroleum",
                "light and tidal",
                "Biogas and alcohol"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Coal and petroleum"
        },
        {
            "question": "The proposed system of education in Nigeria may have not thrived well as expected because of",
            "options": [
                "lack of needed trained personnel",
                "lack of desired professional equipment",
                "lack of fund",
                "excess manpower needed"
            ],
            "correctOption": "lack of needed trained personnel"
        },
        {
            "question": "The quality of a good graduate is shown in his",
            "options": [
                "way of dancing",
                "way of actions and behaviours",
                "way of walking",
                "way of eating"
            ],
            "correctOption": "way of actions and behaviours"
        },
        {
            "question": "An electric device is rated at 250W, 250V, the correct fuse rating for the device is",
            "options": [
                "8A",
                "10A",
                "6A",
                "11A"
            ],
            "correctOption": "11A"
        },
        {
            "question": "The general studies programme is useful in the following ways except",
            "options": [
                "To equip them have critical appreciation of the ways in which they gain knowledge",
                "understanding of themselves, the society and usefulness of known academic disciplines",
                "To equip them as how to organize labour meetings and strikes",
                "Intended to equip student with common knowledge"
            ],
            "correctOption": "To equip them as how to organize labour meetings and strikes"
        },
        {
            "question": "The sample variance is obtained by",
            "options": [
                "squaring the variance",
                "taking the square root of the standard deviation",
                "squaring the standard deviation",
                "(x-x)^2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "squaring the standard deviation"
        },
        {
            "question": "The curve that tails off to the left end is",
            "options": [
                "Symmetrical",
                "skewed right",
                "positively skewed",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "None of these"
        },
        {
            "question": "Component bar chart must consist of except:",
            "options": [
                "equally spaced bars",
                "bars must be of the same width",
                "source of data",
                "scale"
            ],
            "correctOption": "source of data"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the class interval for the set of grouped data 300-349.5, 350-399.5 and 400 - 445.5",
            "options": [
                "50.5",
                "50",
                "49",
                "49.5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "50"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT true when constructing the simple bar chart",
            "options": [
                "same heights",
                "equally spaced bar",
                "the height of the bars",
                "same width"
            ],
            "correctOption": "same heights"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT an example of compressed data?",
            "options": [
                "Data array",
                "Ogive",
                "Histogram",
                "Frequency distribution"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Data array"
        },
        {
            "question": "Given class intervals 10-14, 15-19, 20-24 and 25-29 with frequencies 4, 2, 5, and 1 respectively. What is the modal class?",
            "options": [
                "10-14",
                "25-29",
                "15-19",
                "20-24"
            ],
            "correctOption": "20-24"
        },
        {
            "question": "How does the computation of sample variance differ from that of the population variance",
            "options": [
                "N is replaced by n-1",
                "μ is replaced by x & N is replaced by n-1",
                "μ is replaced by x",
                "N is replaced by n"
            ],
            "correctOption": "μ is replaced by x & N is replaced by n-1"
        },
        {
            "question": "In solving problems statistically all the following steps are involved except:",
            "options": [
                "Decision making",
                "Presentation of data",
                "Organization of data",
                "Interpretation of data"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Decision making"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statement about the histogram is true",
            "options": [
                "The bars are all equal in height",
                "The areas of the histogram is of no meaning",
                "The bars are all equal in width",
                "The bars are all equal in size"
            ],
            "correctOption": "The bars are all equal in width"
        },
        {
            "question": "Suppose the modal class is 100-149.5 find the lower class limit",
            "options": [
                "100",
                "99",
                "99.9",
                "99.5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "100"
        },
        {
            "question": "Descriptive statistics is science of describing the important characteristics of a:",
            "options": [
                "skewness",
                "sample",
                "Population",
                "population or sample"
            ],
            "correctOption": "population or sample"
        },
        {
            "question": "When constructing a multiple bar chart, the following are necessary except",
            "options": [
                "array of data",
                "key",
                "table",
                "a scale"
            ],
            "correctOption": "array of data"
        },
        {
            "question": "Graphs of frequency distributions are used because",
            "options": [
                "They account for biased or incomplete data",
                "They have a long history in practical applications",
                "They allow for easy estimates of values",
                "Information contained in it cannot be easily understood"
            ],
            "correctOption": "They allow for easy estimates of values"
        },
        {
            "question": "Two methods of data arrangement are:",
            "options": [
                "Data array and data entering",
                "Data array and frequency distribution",
                "Tally the observations",
                "Frequency coding distribution and data"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Data array and frequency distribution"
        },
        {
            "question": "When solving problem statistically, the step that requires some knowledge of elementary mathematics is known as",
            "options": [
                "Data interpretation",
                "Data organization",
                "Data analysis",
                "Data presentation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Data analysis"
        },
        {
            "question": "From a data array with 50 observations, the median will be the value of the:",
            "options": [
                "sum of the 25th and 26th observations",
                "mean value of the 26th and 27th observation",
                "Average value of the 25th and 26th observation",
                "25th observation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "sum of the 25th and 26th observations"
        },
        {
            "question": "Data analysis is a step after _____",
            "options": [
                "Data collection",
                "Data organization",
                "data presentation",
                "Data interpretation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "data presentation"
        },
        {
            "question": "The first step in calculating the median of a data set is:",
            "options": [
                "Arrange the data in ascending or descending order of magnitude",
                "determine the position of the median",
                "Average the middle two values of the data set",
                "Determine the relative weights of the data values in terms of importance"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Arrange the data in ascending or descending order of magnitude"
        },
        {
            "question": "Continuous data are differentiated from discrete data in that",
            "options": [
                "Continuous data classes may be represented by fraction",
                "Discrete number data can take on any real number",
                "Continuous numbers data take on only whole",
                "Discrete data classes are represented by fraction"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Discrete number data can take on any real number"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following represent the most accurate scheme of classifying data",
            "options": [
                "Qualitative methods",
                "A combination of quantitative and qualitative methods",
                "A scheme can be determined only with specific information about the situation",
                "Quantitative methods"
            ],
            "correctOption": "A scheme can be determined only with specific information about the situation"
        },
        {
            "question": "When constructing a frequency distribution for a sample, the number of classes depends on",
            "options": [
                "the range of the data collected",
                "the size of the population",
                "smallest observation",
                "The number of data points"
            ],
            "correctOption": "the range of the data collected"
        },
        {
            "question": "A relative frequency distribution presents frequencies in terms of",
            "options": [
                "percentages",
                "fraction",
                "whole number",
                "whole number and percentages"
            ],
            "correctOption": "fraction"
        },
        {
            "question": "Data can be compressed into the following except:",
            "options": [
                "polygon",
                "picture diagram",
                "pie chart",
                "cumulative frequency curve"
            ],
            "correctOption": "picture diagram"
        },
        {
            "question": "Write the upper class limit of the set of grouped data 300-349.5, 350-399.5 and 400-449.5",
            "options": [
                "349.55, 399.55",
                "349.55, 399.55, 449.5",
                "349.55, 350, 449.5",
                "349.5, 399.5, 449.5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "349.5, 399.5, 449.5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the measures of central tendency take into account the value of every observations in the data",
            "options": [
                "median",
                "mean",
                "mode",
                "range"
            ],
            "correctOption": "mean"
        },
        {
            "question": "A good chart must NOT have:",
            "options": [
                "stubs",
                "Title",
                "a scale",
                "a key where necessary"
            ],
            "correctOption": "stubs"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a measure of dispersion",
            "options": [
                "mean",
                "harmonic mean",
                "mode",
                "standard deviation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "harmonic mean"
        },
        {
            "question": "Given the class interval of the modal class as 100-149.5 what is the lowest class boundary",
            "options": [
                "99",
                "99.95",
                "99.5",
                "100"
            ],
            "correctOption": "99.5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Ectoparasites live",
            "options": [
                "Beside the hosts",
                "inside",
                "outside",
                "inside and outside"
            ],
            "correctOption": "outside"
        },
        {
            "question": "Balantidiumcoli is a",
            "options": [
                "Ciliate",
                "Nematode",
                "Flagellate",
                "Arthropod"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ciliate"
        },
        {
            "question": "An example of intracellular parasite is",
            "options": [
                "Plasmodium",
                "AIDS",
                "Roundworm",
                "Flea"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Plasmodium"
        },
        {
            "question": "The job of a vector is to",
            "options": [
                "Destroy the parasite",
                "Transmits parasite to the host",
                "Destroy the host"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Transmits parasite to the host"
        },
        {
            "question": "Obligate plant parasites",
            "options": [
                "Need vectors to survive",
                "does not need host to survive",
                "Need host to survive"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Need host to survive"
        },
        {
            "question": "An example of intracellular parasite is",
            "options": [
                "Blood fluke",
                "Tse-tse fly",
                "Aedes mosquito"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Blood fluke"
        },
        {
            "question": "An example of endoparasites is",
            "options": [
                "Plasmodium",
                "trick",
                "mite",
                "crab"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Plasmodium"
        },
        {
            "question": "The disease caused by infection of Amoeba is",
            "options": [
                "Air borne",
                "Animal borne",
                "Water borne"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Water borne"
        },
        {
            "question": "Intercellular Parasites inhabits",
            "options": [
                "Places of the hosts",
                "Tissues",
                "Cells",
                "Spaces"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Places of the hosts"
        },
        {
            "question": "An example of an ectoparasite is a",
            "options": [
                "Mosquito",
                "Hookworm",
                "Tick",
                "Fluke"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Tick"
        },
        {
            "question": "Malaria fever is caused by infection of",
            "options": [
                "Mosquito",
                "Paramecium",
                "Mite",
                "Plasmodium"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Plasmodium"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mosquito is a vector of",
            "options": [
                "Paramecium",
                "Plasmodium",
                "Ascaris",
                "Malaria"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Plasmodium"
        },
        {
            "question": "Plant parasites obtain food from the host's",
            "options": [
                "Cambium",
                "Xylem",
                "Leaves",
                "Phloem"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Phloem"
        },
        {
            "question": "Giardia lamblia is a parasite of",
            "options": [
                "Heart",
                "Liver",
                "Large intestine",
                "Small intestines"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Small intestines"
        },
        {
            "question": "A protozoan is",
            "options": [
                "Singled cell",
                "Bicellular",
                "Does not exist",
                "Multicellular"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Singled cell"
        },
        {
            "question": "Endoparasites live a Inside and outside",
            "options": [
                "Beside the hosts",
                "Outside",
                "Inside",
                "Inside and outside"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Inside"
        },
        {
            "question": "Obligates plant parasites",
            "options": [
                "can survive on their own",
                "are photosynthetic",
                "are non-photosynthetic"
            ],
            "correctOption": "are non-photosynthetic"
        },
        {
            "question": "A host also",
            "options": [
                "Benefits",
                "Does not benefits",
                "sometimes parasites benefits from the"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Does not benefits"
        },
        {
            "question": "Balantidium coliis a parasite of",
            "options": [
                "Heart",
                "Large intestine",
                "Small intestine",
                "Liver"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Large intestine"
        },
        {
            "question": "Giardia lamblia is a",
            "options": [
                "Platyhelminthes",
                "Protozoan",
                "Flagellate",
                "Nematode"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Flagellate"
        },
        {
            "question": "The circulation of mineral nutrient between the plants and the soil is called",
            "options": [
                "Nutrient cycle",
                "Hydrogen cycle",
                "Carbon cycle",
                "Nitrogen cycle"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Nutrient cycle"
        },
        {
            "question": "Development touches on the following except",
            "options": [
                "Self esteem",
                "Dignity",
                "Ego",
                "Freedom"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ego"
        },
        {
            "question": "Man is classified under autotrophs",
            "options": [
                "composers",
                "decomposers",
                "heterotrophs",
                "autotrophs"
            ],
            "correctOption": "heterotrophs"
        },
        {
            "question": "The process through which land receives water include the following except",
            "options": [
                "Infiltration",
                "Rainfall",
                "Evapotranspiration",
                "Percolation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Evapotranspiration"
        },
        {
            "question": "Land reclamation has no effect on the soil moisture content",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "The relationship between plants, animals and the environment is called:",
            "options": [
                "Ecotype",
                "Ecosystem",
                "Communication",
                "Interaction"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ecosystem"
        },
        {
            "question": "Land pollution causes the loss of plants and animals",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "The part of the earth which contains the rocks, soil and minerals is called:",
            "options": [
                "Biosphere",
                "Atmosphere",
                "Lithosphere",
                "Hydrosphere"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Lithosphere"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nitrogen is found in the:",
            "options": [
                "Lithosphere",
                "Land",
                "Water",
                "Atmosphere"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Atmosphere"
        },
        {
            "question": "Over grazing has no significant effect on vegetation",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Animals decompose to form manure for plants",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Plant take in  ____________  during photosynthesis",
            "options": [
                "Oxygen",
                "Nitrogen",
                "Hydrogen",
                "Carbon dioxide"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Carbon dioxide"
        },
        {
            "question": "Coal, Petroleum resources are not found in rocks",
            "options": [
                "Water",
                "Sand",
                "Atmosphere",
                "Rock"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Atmosphere"
        },
        {
            "question": "To course something to start means",
            "options": [
                "Developed",
                "Underdevelopment",
                "Developing",
                "Development"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Developing"
        },
        {
            "question": "Organic matter contained in the soil is affected by farming activities",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Living organism do not need water for normal life process",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Natural intervention leads to  ____________  of animals",
            "options": [
                "Attraction",
                "Extinction",
                "Displacement",
                "Redistribution"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Displacement"
        },
        {
            "question": "The redistribution and improvement in the welfare and quality of life of the people is",
            "options": [
                "Sustained defeat",
                "Development",
                "Sustainable development",
                "Sustainable defeat"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Sustainable development"
        },
        {
            "question": "Development adds to improvement in",
            "options": [
                "Income",
                "Output",
                "Input",
                "Income and Output"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Income and Output"
        },
        {
            "question": "The capacity to deal with the environment involves:",
            "options": [
                "(ii) Ability to harness the environmental resources",
                "ii & iii",
                "(iii) High technological ability to modify the environment",
                "(i) Poor technology to harness environmental resources"
            ],
            "correctOption": "ii & iii"
        },
        {
            "question": "Oil spillage and water pollution do not alter the type of plants and animals that can survive in the ecosystem",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Hydrosphere is the part of the earth that contains:",
            "options": [
                "Plant",
                "Sand",
                "Water",
                "Rocks"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Water"
        },
        {
            "question": "The spheres of the earth is grouped into:",
            "options": [
                "5",
                "3",
                "4",
                "7"
            ],
            "correctOption": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "The recycling and flow of energy within the ecosystem is called",
            "options": [
                "Ecobalance",
                "Environmental disturbance",
                "Environmental balance",
                "Energy flow"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Environmental balance"
        },
        {
            "question": "The process of rapid Economic growth is",
            "options": [
                "Development",
                "Stabilization in the Gross National Product",
                "Reduction in economic resources",
                "Economic stagnation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Development"
        },
        {
            "question": "The environment includes the following except:",
            "options": [
                "Physical surrounding",
                "Living organisms",
                "All of these",
                "Climatic factors"
            ],
            "correctOption": "All of these"
        },
        {
            "question": "Denitrification is the major way by which ____________ is lost from the soil.",
            "options": [
                "Hydrogen",
                "Carbon dioxide",
                "Nitrates",
                "Oxygen"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Nitrates"
        },
        {
            "question": "Soil, water and gases are living things:",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Plants produces ____________ during photosynthesis",
            "options": [
                "Carbon dioxide",
                "Soil",
                "Oxygen",
                "water"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Oxygen"
        },
        {
            "question": "The forces of nature and the activities of man that change the natural component of the ecosystem is referred as:",
            "options": [
                "environmental relationship",
                "Environmental change",
                "Environmental intervention",
                "Environmental planning"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Environmental intervention"
        }
    ]
}